Guide to the Yale University Press Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Records, circa 1910-1979; Accession 1990-A-042
  - Chronicles of America: Pageant of America; Correspondence
    - Wilton Rubenstein, undated (Box 18, Folder 952)
    - A.M. Schlesinger Sr., 1924 (Box 18, Folder 953)
    - Charles Seymour, 1925 (Box 18, Folder 954)
    - F.E. Spaulding, 1924-25 (Box 18, Folder 955)
    - Lilian Brown Stockwell, 1923 (Box 18, Folder 956)
    - Anson Phelps Stokes, 1924-25 (Box 18, Folder 957)
    - Time Magazine, 1926 (Box 18, Folder 958)
    - John Hay Whitney, 1937-1941 (Box 18, Folder 959)
    - Payne Whitney, 1924 (Box 18, Folder 960)
  - Publishing and Graphic Arts (The Atlantic Monthly Publishers Weekly), 1929-1930 (Box 18, Folder 961)
  - Publishing and Graphic Arts - AIGA Fifty Books of the Year
    - 1929-1930 (Box 18, Folder 962)
    - 1932-1935 (Box 18, Folder 963)
    - 1936-1937, 1939, 1941, 1945 (Box 18, Folder 964)
    - 1950, 1956, 1962 (Box 18, Folder 965)
    - 1963-1964 (Box 18, Folder 966)
  - AIGA List of Members and Miscellaneous Newsletters and Flyers, 1928-1961 (Box 18, Folder 967)
  - Vinland Map News Clippings and Programs, 1963-1967 (Box 18, Folder 968)
  - Vinland Map - Book, Magazine Articles, 1963-1966 (Box 18, Folder 969)
  - Vinland Map Clippings, 1965 (Box 18, Folder 970)
  - Vinland Map Press Cuttings for YUP, USA, 1965 (Box 18, Folder 971)
  - Chronicles of America: Pageant of America
    - Correspondence
      - Arthur H. Brook (George Washington Bicentennial Etchings - I, 1932-1937 (Box 19, Folder 972)
      - Bicentennial Etchings, 1932 (Box 19, Folder 973 - 974)
      - P.J. Cormican, S.J., 1925 (Box 19, Folder 975)
      - Admiral R. Byrd, 1935 (Box 19, Folder 976)
      - Irving M. Countryman, 1925 (Box 19, Folder 977)
      - Dr. Harvey Cushing, 1926 (Box 19, Folder 978)
      - William Todd De Van, 1922 (Box 19, Folder 979)
      - Bernard De Voto, 1937-1938 (Box 19, Folder 980)
      - W.H. Dudley, 1930 (Box 19, Folder 981)
      - Margaret Elder, 1925 (Box 19, Folder 982)
      - Max Ferrand, 1925 (Box 19, Folder 983)
      - Edsel Ford, 1927 (Box 19, Folder 984)
      - Smith D. Fry, 1924-25 (Box 19, Folder 985)
      - Clara Fuller, 1938 (Box 19, Folder 986)
      - Ralph Gabriel, 1926-27 (Box 19, Folder 987)
      - Dr. Arnold Gesell, 1927 (Box 19, Folder 988)
      - Robert Glasgow, 1919-1922 (Box 19, Folder 989)
      - J.W. Hamilton, 1926-1927 (Box 19, Folder 990)
      - Richard Hooker, 1929 (Box 19, Folder 991)
      - Herbert Hoover, 1925 (Box 19, Folder 992)
      - Allen Johnson, 1920-1925 (Box 19, Folder 993)
      - Daniel Knowlton, 1927-1929 (Box 19, Folder 994)
      - Little, Brown and Co., 1939 (Box 19, Folder 995)
      - Janet R. Marshall, 1927 (Box 19, Folder 996)
      - Elmore McKee, 1927 (Box 19, Folder 997)
      - Samuel E. Morrison, 1923 (Box 19, Folder 998)
    - Promotional Materials
      - Volumes, 1916-1926 (Box 19, Folder 999)
      - Movies, 1928-1952 (Box 19, Folder 1000)
      - Photoplays, 1924 (Box 19, Folder 1001)
      - 1926-1956 (Box 19, Folder 1002)
    - Educational Journals
      - The Journal of Social Psychology, The GLF Shareholder, 1930 (Box 19, Folder 1003)
      - Educational Screen and Motion Pictures in Education, 1934 (Box 19, Folder 1004)
      - World Review, Journal of the National Education Association, 1925 (Box 19, Folder 1005)
      - Scholastic, Junior Scholastic, 1939 February (Box 19, Folder 1006)
      - Miscellaneous Journals, 1926-1940 (Box 19, Folder 1007)
  - University Presses (Box 19, Folder 1008)
    - Exhibitions, 1936, 1937, 1946 (Box 19, Folder 1009)
    - Information, 1936-1937, 1947, 1961 (Box 19, Folder 1010)
    - Letters (framed) t o G.P. Day, 1930-1939 (Box 19, Folder 1011)
    - Photo - Eugene Davidson, Norman Donaldson, G.P. Day Chester Kerr, Whitney Griswold (Box 19, Folder 1012)
  - Miscellaneous: Yale Corp. Recognition of George Parmly Day
  - YUP Advance Publications Lists, 1941-1949 (Box 20, Folder 1013)
  - YUP New and Recent Books
    - Spring 1926 - Autumn 1934 (Box 20, Folder 1014)
    - Spring 1935 - Autumn 1940 (Box 20, Folder 1015)
    - Spring 1941 - Holiday 1945 (Box 20, Folder 1016)
    - Spring 1946 - Holiday 1950 (Box 20, Folder 1017)
    - Spring 1951 - Autumn 1955 (Box 20, Folder 1018)
    - Spring 1956 - Autumn 1960 (Box 20, Folder 1019)
    - Spring 1961 - Fall 1965 (Box 20, Folder 1020)
    - Spring 1966 - Fall 1970 (Box 20, Folder 1021)
    - Spring 1971 - Fall 1975 (Box 20, Folder 1022)
    - Spring 1976 - Spring 1980 (Box 20, Folder 1023)
  - Book Jackets, circa1976-1977 (Box 20, Folder 1024)
  - New Books from Chicago-Columbia-Yale and Princeton Presses, 1964-1980 (Box 20, Folder 1025)
  - Yale Books in Print, 1947-1968 (Box 20, Folder 1026)
  - Publishers Weekly, Carey-Thomas Award List to 1977, 1958, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 1027)
  - YUP Exhibit Photographs - Fine Arts, 1929-1965 (Box 21, Folder 1029)
  - Programs, 1914-1976 (Box 21, Folder 1030)
  - Homes of the YUP, 1960-1973 (Box 21, Folder 1031)
  - YUP Type Specimens, 1939 (Box 21, Folder 1032)
  - Miscellaneous YUP, 1959-1965 (Box 21, Folder 1033)
  - Official Notices - T. Maio's Retirement, Thanks to S.B. Lunt, C, E. Trout, 1956-1960 (Box 21, Folder 1034)
  - Old Photos and Framed Documents, circa1937-1943 (Box 21, Folder 1035)
  - YUP Books, Chester Kerr Photos, 1959-1960, 1959-1979 (Box 21, Folder 1036)
  - Miscellaneous Book Covers and Photographs: Yale Books, 1960-1963 (Box 21, Folder 1037)
  - YUP Photographs, 1916-1920 (Box 21, Folder 1038)
  - Publication of Eero Saarinen on His Work; Jacqueline Kennedy Letter, 1964 (Box 21, Folder 1039)
  - Anniversaries of the YUP
    - 50th - Sterling Library Book Exhibit, 1952-1959 (Box 21, Folder 1040)
    - 50th - Theodore Sizer's Hooked Rug, 1958 (Box 21, Folder 1041)
    - 50th - American Assoc. of University Presses Meeting (Box 21, Folder 1042)
    - 25th, 1933 (Box 21, Folder 1043)
    - 50th General, 1958 (Box 21, Folder 1044)
    - 10th, 1937 (Box 21, Folder 1045)
    - 21st Anniversary, 1929 (Box 21, Folder 1046)
  - Press Personnel Lists, 1955-1961 (Box 21, Folder 1047)
  - Archives - General I: Homes of the Press - Photos II Manufacturing and Printing Office II; X-Mas Card, 1959-1973 (Box 21, Folder 1048)
  - YUP and Women, 1930 (Box 21, Folder 1049)
  - Photos of G.P. Day, Mrs. Day, Carl P. Rollins, circa1955-1959 (Box 21, Folder 1050)
  - Ad by Mrs. Day, Photos of YUP Personnel, 1919, 1959 (Box 21, Folder 1051)
  - YUP Magazines, Newsletter, 1958-1968 (Box 21, Folder 1052)
  - 60th Anniversary Dinner, 1968 (Box 21, Folder 1053)
  - Clarence Day Jr., 1920-1923 (Box 21, Folder 1054)
  - Carl Rollins, Chronicles of America, Yale Shakespeare, 1917-1927 (Box 21, Folder 1055)
  - WWI Herbert Hoover Letter, 1916-1917 (Box 21, Folder 1056)
  - YSYP Book Covers: Dickey, Hollander, Merwin, 1919-1977 (Box 21, Folder 1057)
  - George Parmly Day, YUP building - photos, Hadley memo, 1907-1919 (Box 21, Folder 1058)
  - Yale Review, cost of advertising memo, "Diary of a Weeks Publishing", 1911-1914 (Box 21, Folder 1059)
  - Photos: Press Staff, Furniss, Efsenman, Donaldson, Hilles, 50th Anniversary Book Covers: Riesman, O'Neill, Stein, Publishers Weakly, 1950-1963 (Box 21, Folder 1060)
  - Books, Sweden in the Middle Way, 1938-1940 (Box 21, Folder 1061)
  - Lewis, The Yale Ed. of Horace Walpoole's Correspondence; Andrews, The Colonial Period in American History, 1935-1983 (Box 21, Folder 1062)
  - S.V. Benet - YSYP, Clarence Day, Charles Andrews, 1933-1935 (Box 21, Folder 1063)
  - Yale Press Photographs, Clipping of American Book in Education., 1930-1959 (Box 21, Folder 1064)
  - 75th Anniversary - Photos and Clippings, 1983-1984 (Box 21, Folder 1065)
  - 75th Anniversary - Clippings and Exhibit, 1983 (Box 21, Folder 1066)
  - Books/photos - The Vinland Map, Yale Fastback, The Double Cross System, The Horse of Pride, YUP Building, 1965-1978 (Box 21, Folder 1067)
  - John Ryder, Yale Books, Burell's Retirement, Mary Chestnut's Civil War, Miscellaneous Photos, 1979-1983 (Box 21, Folder 1068)
  - Bookman's Weekly, 1983 December 16-25 (Box 21, Folder 1069)
  - 75th Anniversary - Programs, 1983 (Box 21, Folder 1070)
  - Prize-Winning Books, 1982-1983 (Box 21, Folder 1071)
  - Miscellaneous Reports and Articles, 1949-1983 (Box 21, Folder 1072)
  - Chicago, Columbia, Yale London Sales Office Photo, 1961-1965 (Box 21, Folder 1073)
  - First Fifty Years of Yale University Press, 1958; 1; 35 mm microfilm (Reel 22)
  - Oversize
    - George Parmly Day, copy of citation from Yale Corporation on his retirement in 1944, Undated (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Yale University Press building photograph, Circa 1918 (Box 23, Folder 2)
- Records, 1960-1986; Accession 1991-A-019
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2021
  - Correspondence
    - A, 1971-1972 (Box 1)
    - American Association of University Presses (AAUP), 1970-1972 (Box 1)
    - Adams, Frederick B., 1965-1972 (Box 1)
    - Albers: Interaction Correspondence with Mahlow and Kerr, 1970-1971 (Box 1)
    - Association of American Publishers, 1971-1972 (Box 1)
    - Abel, Richard and Company, 1971-1972 (Box 1)
    - Ad Hoc Committee on the Relationship of the Press to the University, 1971-1972 (Box 1)
    - Archon Books, 1967-1971 (Box 1)
    - Australia and New Zealand Book Co. Pty. Ltd., 1967-1971 (Box 1)
    - Authors' Christmas Party, 1971 (Box 1)
    - Ahlstrom, Sydney E., 1970-1972 (Box 1)
    - Alsop, Stewart, 1971-1972 (Box 1)
    - B, 1971-1972 (Box 1)
    - Bracher-Sauer-Schulz, 1963-1972 (Box 1)
    - Brecher, Michael: Foreign Policy System of Israel, 1971-1972 (Box 1)
    - Barany, George: University of Denver, 1970-1971 (Box 1)
    - Badash, Lawrence, 1969-1970 (Box 1)
    - Bowker, R.R. Company, 1970-1971 (Box 1)
    - British Museum, 1970-1971 (Box 1)
    - Brown, J. Trevor: IBEG Ltd., 1971-1972 (Box 1)
    - Brewster, Kingman, Jr., 1971-1972 (Box 1)
    - C, 1971-1972 (Box 1)
    - Cambridge University Press, 1971-1972 (Box 1)
    - Canadian-American Series, 1969-1971 (Box 1)
    - Cassirer Lectures, 1972 (Box 1)
    - Carter, Ted: Latrobe Papers, 1971-1972 (Box 1)
    - Columbia University Press, 1971-1972 (Box 1)
    - Centro Interamericano de Libros Academicos (CILA), 1967-1971 (Box 1)
    - Centrex, 1969-1972 (Box 1)
    - Chauncey, Henry, Jr., 1971-1972 (Box 1)
    - Cappon, Lester J.: Atlas of Early American History, 1971 (Box 1)
    - D, 1971-1972 (Box 1)
    - Donaldson, Virginia, 1964-1970 (Box 1)
    - Doob, Leonard W., 1971-1972 (Box 1)
    - Dreyfus, John, 1969-1972 (Box 1)
    - Dahl, Robert A., 1969-1972 (Box 1)
    - Department Heads, Memos to, 1971-1972 (Box 1)
    - E, 1968-1972 (Box 1)
    - Editorial Department, 1971-1972 (Box 1)
    - F, 1971-1972 (Box 1)
    - Faber and Faber Ltd., 1967-1971 (Box 1)
    - Franklin Papers: Complimentary Copies, 1959-1960 (Box 1)
    - Franklin, Benjamin Series, 1969-1970 (Box 1)
    - G, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
    - Gilead, Dorothea Krook, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
    - Goldsen, Joseph M., 1971-1972 (Box 2)
    - Governing Board, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
    - H, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
    - Holden, Reuben A., 1972 (Box 2)
    - Hambro, Edvard, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
    - Hayes, John: The Drawings of Thomas Gainsborough, 1970 (Box 2)
    - I, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
    - International Copyrights Information Center (INCINC) Committee, 1969-1971 (Box 2)
    - J, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
    - Jenkins, Roy H., 1971-1973 (Box 2)
    - Johnson, Samuel, Works of, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
    - K, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
    - Kennedy, David M., 1971 (Box 2)
    - Kerr, Chester: Jerusalem, 1971 (Box 2)
    - Kerr, Chester: Miscellaneous, 1970-1972 (Box 2)
    - Kunitz, Stanley, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
    - L, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
    - Lewis, Wilmarth S., 1971-1972 (Box 2)
    - Liebert, Herman W., 1970-1972 (Box 2)
    - M, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
    - Mansbridge, F. Ronald, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
    - McGill University Press: Robin Stracham, 1969-1972 (Box 2)
    - Mellon Center for British Art, 1969-1972 (Box 2)
    - Mellon Foundation Grant, 1972 (Box 2)
    - Memos to the Staff, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
    - Muller Printing Machinery Company, 1970-1971 (Box 2)
    - More, St. Thomas, Edition, 1969-1972 (Box 2)
    - Myers, Robert: "Children of Pride", 1970-1972 (Box 2)
    - N, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
    - National Book Committee, 1970-1972 (Box 2)
    - New Haven Jewish Community Center, 1960-1972 (Box 2)
    - Newsweek, 1969-1972 (Box 2)
    - New York Historical Society, 1971 (Box 2)
    - Newton-Erikson Dialogue, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
    - O, 1971-1972 (Box 3)
    - P, 1971-1972 (Box 3)
    - Parker, Beulah, 1972 (Box 3)
    - Paulson, Ronald, 1970-1972 (Box 3)
    - Pratt, D.J., 1966-1972 (Box 3)
    - Publications, Committee on, 1971-1972 (Box 3)
    - Printing and Design, Committee on, 1972 (Box 3)
    - Popham, 1967-1971 (Box 3)
    - Pollard, Phyllis Bartlett, 1970-1971 (Box 3)
    - Princeton University Press, 1971-1972 (Box 3)
    - Prown, Jules, 1971-1972 (Box 3)
    - Publishers' Lunch Club, 1968-1972 (Box 3)
    - Phelan, Howard, 1967-1972 (Box 3)
    - Printing and Design, Committee on: Memos, 1971-1972 (Box 3)
    - Publication Schedules, 1957-1971 (Box 3)
    - R, 1971-1972 (Box 3)
    - Reynolds, Lloyd, 1971 (Box 3)
    - Rheault, Charles, 1970-1971 (Box 3)
    - Ryskamp, Charles, 1971-1972 (Box 3)
    - S, 1971-1972 (Box 3)
    - Simmons, Leo, 1971 (Box 3)
    - Skelton and Victor: Map Portfolio, 1967-1970 (Box 3)
    - Steiner, George, 1971-1972 (Box 3)
    - Schmitt, Wayland, 1971 (Box 3)
    - Singapore Book Fair, 1970-1971 (Box 3)
    - Science Series, 1969-1971 (Box 3)
    - Services Committee: Study Commission on Governance, 1971 (Box 3)
    - Smith, Morgan K., 1971-1972 (Box 3)
    - T, 1971-1972 (Box 3)
    - Taylor, Charles H., 1971-1972 (Box 3)
    - U, 1971-1972 (Box 3)
    - United States Publishers Association, 1969-1971 (Box 3)
    - Universitet Sforlaget, 1971-1972 (Box 3)
    - University of Toronto Press, 1970-1972 (Box 3)
    - University of Florida Press, 1971-1972 (Box 3)
    - University of Texas Press, 1971-1972 (Box 3)
    - University Series, 1966-1967 (Box 3)
    - University Council's Committee on Publications, 1957-1962 (Box 3)
    - V, 1971-1972 (Box 3)
    - W, 1971-1972 (Box 4)
    - Western History Association, 1965-1972 (Box 4)
    - Western History Association: Hotel Reservations, 1972 (Box 4)
    - Western History Association: New Haven Conference, 1972 (Box 4)
    - Western Office of Yale University: Frank W. Schork, Jr., 1971 (Box 4)
    - Wilkie, Peter, 1971-1972 (Box 4)
    - Winks, Robin W., 1969-1972 (Box 4)
    - X-Y-Z, 1971-1972 (Box 4)
    - Yale Corral, 1968-1970 (Box 4)
    - Yale Reader's Handbook, 1972 (Box 4)
    - Yale University Press Parking Lot, 1960-1971 (Box 4)
    - Yale University Press, Ltd., 1970-1971 (Box 4)
    - Yale University Press: Miscellaneous Memos, 1971 (Box 4)
    - Zangrando, Robert, 1969-1971 (Box 4)
    - Zokeisha Publications Ltd.: Tokyo, 1970-1972 (Box 4)
    - Zwemmer, A., Ltd., 1971 (Box 4)
    - A, 1973-1974 (Box 5)
    - Adams, Frederick B., 1973-1974 (Box 5)
    - Alsop, Stewart, 1973-1974 (Box 5)
    - American Association of University Presses (AAUP), 1973-1974 (Box 5)
    - Association of American Publishers, 1973-1974 (Box 5)
    - American Heritage, 1973-1974 (Box 5)
    - Ad Hoc Committee on What to Publish, 1973 (Box 5)
    - B, 1973-1974 (Box 5)
    - Black, Charles L., 1974 (Box 5)
    - Blake, Whitney, 1970-1974 (Box 5)
    - Booth Papers, 1966-1986 (Box 5)
    - Boyden, J.W., 1973-1974 (Box 5)
    - Bookout I and Bookout II, 1973-1974 (Box 5)
    - Brewster, Kingman, 1973-1974 (Box 5)
    - Brown, Irene, 1970-1977 (Box 5)
    - C, 1973-1974 (Box 5)
    - Chauncy, Henry, 1973-1974 (Box 5)
    - Cholmeley, Jane, 1974 (Box 5)
    - Crutchley, Brooke, 1973-1974 (Box 5)
    - Curwen Press, Ltd., 1973-1974 (Box 5)
    - D, 1973-1974 (Box 5)
    - Department Heads, 1973-1974 (Box 5)
    - Dreyfus, John, 1973-1974 (Box 5)
    - E, 1973-1974 (Box 5)
    - Ecklund, John E., 1967-1974 (Box 5)
    - Editorial Department, 1973-1974 (Box 5)
    - Executive Committee, 1974 (Box 5)
    - Employment, 1973-1974 (Box 5)
    - F, 1973-1974 (Box 5)
    - Finance, Committee on, 1973-1974 (Box 5)
    - Faber and Faber, Ltd: P.F. du Santoy, 1973-1974 (Box 5)
    - G, 1972-1974 (Box 6)
    - Governing Board, 1973-1974 (Box 6)
    - H, 1973-1974 (Box 6)
    - I, 1973-1974 (Box 6)
    - J, 1973-1974 (Box 6)
    - K, 1973-1974 (Box 6)
    - Kellogg, Chris, 1974-1976 (Box 6)
    - Kerr, Chester, 1973-1974 (Box 6)
    - Kling, D.W., 1972-1974 (Box 6)
    - L, 1973-1974 (Box 6)
    - M, 1973-1974 (Box 6)
    - Masterman, John, 1971-1974 (Box 6)
    - Masterman: Extra Copies of Documents, 1971 (Box 6)
    - Mellon Chansonnier, 1967-1969 (Box 6)
    - Mellon Center for Studies in British Art, 1973-1974 (Box 6)
    - Moore-Plyle: Yale Math Building, 1974 (Box 6)
    - Magnolia Hall, 1973 (Box 6)
    - Memos to the Staff, 1973-1974 (Box 6)
    - N, 1972-1974 (Box 6)
    - Newsweek, 1973-1974 (Box 6)
    - Nominations, Committee on, 1974 (Box 6)
    - O, 1974 (Box 6)
    - P, 1973-1974 (Box 6)
    - Parker, Beulah, 1973-1974 (Box 6)
    - Personnel, 1969-1973 (Box 6)
    - Publications, Committee on, 1973-1974 (Box 6)
    - Princeton University Press, 1973-1974 (Box 6)
    - Pratt, Dana J., 1973-1974 (Box 6)
    - Picnic, 1967-1969 (Box 6)
    - Q, 1973-1974 (Box 6)
    - R, 1973-1974 (Box 7)
    - Ryskamp, Charles, 1973-1974 (Box 7)
    - S, 1973-1974 (Box 7)
    - Silver Springs Farm Center, 1973-1974 (Box 7)
    - Seltzer, Leon E., 1973-1974 (Box 7)
    - Smith, Morgan K., 1973-1974 (Box 7)
    - Solmit, Albert J., 1973-1974 (Box 7)
    - T, 1973-1974 (Box 7)
    - U, 1973-1974 (Box 7)
    - United States Publishers Association, 1973-1974 (Box 7)
    - University of Massachusetts Press, 1973-1974 (Box 7)
    - Universitets Forlaget, 1973-1974 (Box 7)
    - V, 1973-1974 (Box 7)
    - W, 1973-1974 (Box 7)
    - Wark, Robert, 1974 (Box 7)
    - Western History Association, 1974 (Box 7)
    - Wolfe, Don M., 1973-1974 (Box 7)
    - X-Y-Z, 1973-1974 (Box 7)
    - Yale Clubs, 1965-1974 (Box 7)
    - Yale University Press Library and Archives, 1968 (Box 7)
    - Yale Math Building, 1973 (Box 7)
    - Yale University Press Staff Association, 1971-1972 (Box 7)
    - Yale University Press, Ltd. (London), 1973 (Box 7)
    - Yale University Press, Ltd. (London), 1974 (Box 7)
- Records of John G. Ryden as Director, 1979-2003; Accession 2004-A-164
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2038
  - Authors Taxes (Box 1)
  - Authors A-D, 1994-2003 (Box 1)
  - Adams, Howard, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Ahern, Edwards, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Bergin, Thomas G., 1981-1985 (Box 1)
  - Black, Charlie, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Brown, Elizabeth Mills, 1975-1986 (Box 1)
  - Brown, Robert McAfee, 1983-1985 (Box 1)
  - Capretz, Pierre J. and Barry Lydgate, 1985-2000 (Box 1)
  - Chen, Lung-Chu, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Cohen, Donald, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Conklin, Harold C., 1982-1984 (Box 1)
  - Dahl, Robert, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Decker, Wolfgang, 1990-1992 (Box 1)
  - Dizikes, John, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Authors E-H, 1991-2001 (Box 1)
  - Erikson, Kai, 1995-1998 (Box 1)
  - Fleming, Stuart Dr., 1997 (Box 1)
  - Flink, Stanley, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Forte, Allen, 1979-2000 (Box 1)
  - Gay, Peter, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Giamatti, A. Bartlett, 1977-1992 (Box 1)
  - Girouard, Mark, 1978-1985 (Box 1)
  - Green, Richard, 1982-1989 (Box 1)
  - Hamilton, Nigel, 1979-1981 (Box 1)
  - Haynes, John, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Hexter, Jack H., 1980-1995 (Box 1)
  - Hickey, Leo J. (Professor), 1993 (Box 1)
  - Authors I-M, 1979-1982 (Box 1)
  - Izenour, George C., 1997-2000 (Box 1)
  - Kennedy, Emmet, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Koeppel, Gerard, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Kovar, Lillian, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Lukacs, John, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Mailing list/New Haven Authors (Box 1)
  - Martz, Louis L., 1975-1985 (Box 1)
  - Murray, K.M. Elisabeth, 1977-1979 (Box 1)
  - Authors N-Z, 1988-2001 (Box 1)
  - Niebuhr, Reinhold, 1983-1987 (Box 1)
  - Ohl, Vicki, 2000 (Box 1)
  - O'Neill, Eugene, 1966-1993 (Box 1)
  - Rand, Paul, 1985-1993 (Box 1)
  - Rosenthal, Bernice Glatzer, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Schenker, Alexander M., 1997-1998 (Box 1)
  - Schimdt, Helmut, 1985-1986 (Box 1)
  - Schrader and Schebera, 1989 (Box 1)
  - Scott, James C., 1982-1999 (Box 1)
  - Sinclair, Jim (Box 1)
  - Smith, John E., 1979-2000 (Box 1)
  - Sonnenfeld, Leni, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Stilgoe, John R., 1984-2000 (Box 1)
  - Thompson, Bradbury, 1986-1991 (Box 1)
  - Tucker, Paul Hayes, 1981-1982 (Box 1)
  - Turner, Frank, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Weber, Nick, 1996-2001 (Box 1)
  - Welleck, Rene, 1980-1990 (Box 1)
  - Whiteside, Thomas, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Wilder, Amos Tappan, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Winn, James A., 1988 (Box 1)
  - Wiseman, Carter, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Woodward, C. Vann, 1978-1988 (Box 1)
  - Wright, Carol V., 1997 (Box 1)
  - Young-Bruehl, Elisabeth, 1979-1992 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence A, 1983-2001 (Box 1)
  - Adams, Howard, 1999-2001 (Box 2)
  - Adams, Seibert, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence B, 1979-2002 (Box 1)
  - Blum, John, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Boorstin, Daniel J., 1987-1990 (Box 1)
  - Bradley, George, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence C, 1980-2002 (Box 1)
  - Chestnut, David R., 1997 (Box 1)
  - Christopher, Warren, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Cohen, Ellen, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence D, 1988-2002 (Box 1)
  - Davidson, Joan, 1991-1993 (Box 1)
  - DelFattore, Joan, 1993 (Box 1)
  - De Montebello, Phillipe, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence E, 1983-2001 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence F, 1992-1998 (Box 1)
  - Fleming, Stuart, 1980-1993 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence G, 1985-2002 (Box 1)
  - Garfield, Johanna, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Garten, Jeffery, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Gill, Brendan, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Golman, Mirian/Martin, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Grafton, Anthony, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Grossner, Isabel S., 1985-1986 (Box 1)
  - Guinzburg, Thomas H., 2000 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence H, 1988-2003 (Box 1)
  - Hart, Faith Brabenec, 1993-1994 (Box 1)
  - Hoopes, Townsend, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence J/K, 1979-2002 (Box 1)
  - Jervis, Nancy, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Kassier, Jerry, 1999-2000 (Box 1)
  - Kerr, Chester, 1979-1998 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence L, 1979-2002 (Box 1)
  - Lewis, Richard, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Linz, Mark, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence M, 1985-2002 (Box 1)
  - MacDougal, Alfred, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Mansbridge, Ronald, 1993-1999 (Box 1)
  - Miller, Cassey/Swift, Kate, 1992-1994 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence N/O, 1980-2001 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence P, 1980-2002 (Box 1)
  - Peck, Jim, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Pincus, Steven J., 1994 (Box 1)
  - Pratt, Dana J., 1993 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence R, 1979-2002 (Box 1)
  - Reed, Joeseph Verner, 2000-2002 (Box 1)
  - Ryden, Edmund SJ, PhD, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence S, 1980-2001 (Box 1)
  - Sapir, Phillip, 1982-1985 (Box 1)
  - Schlesinger, Arthur, Jr., 1996-1997 (Box 1)
  - Schulman, Jack, 1999-2000 (Box 1)
  - Sewall, Richard, 1991-1993 (Box 1)
  - Smith, Datus C., Jr., 1982-1989 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence T, 1980-2000 (Box 1)
  - Taylor, Alexander, 1993-1995 (Box 1)
  - Tripp, Edward, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Turner, Frank, 1999-2000 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence U/V, 1988-2001 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence W, 1982-2002 (Box 1)
  - Wallace, Thomas C., 2000 (Box 1)
  - Wedgewood, Ruth, 1989 (Box 1)
  - Weeks, Brigitte, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Wilder, Tappy, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Wong, Olivia, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Woodward, C. Vann, 1997 (Box 1)
- Administrative records, including directors and board of governors files, circa 1938-2004; Accession 2006-A-052
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2039
  - Administrative records
    - Endpapers (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Memos to Staff (JGR) (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Applicants (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Assistant to the Director Search (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Development Officer Search (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Director Search, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Language Editor Search (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Burrell, John W. (Box 1, Folder 8)